=Episode 18=
Jin Yunlie,
can you please stay?
Can't you stay with me a little longer?
I want to stay with you too.
But I believe
that even without me,
you can keep living, and live well.
So,
for me,
please don't give up.
Jin Yunlie!
No!
♪The reeds will fade,
and reunion may bring longing♪
♪Green buds wither.
Does my old love still wait?♪
♪When deadwood blooms,
the world turns beautiful♪
♪I'm afraid the snow will melt♪
It worked.
♪I fear this longing
will turn my hair white♪
♪Your tears can defeat
an army of thousands♪
Xi Yuan.
I have very little Spiritual Power left.
This is all I can do for you.
If we meet again,
I hope
you'll possess the power
to slay a deity.
Xi Yuan.
Now that you have a phoenix body,
maybe this time,
we'll actually succeed.
But if you ever find out
I orchestrated all of this,
you might hate me for it.
Who are you?
Jin Yunlie.
You won't die.
Nirvana.
Jin Yunlie.
You can't die.
I'm fine.
We're alive.
This is...
We're alive!
Xi Yuan.
Yunlie.
Where are you?
Miss Xi Yuan.
Did you save us?
Thank you!
Xi Yuan.
Yunlie...
What happened to Yunlie?
Phoenix.
Jin Yunlie is dead.
Why couldn't I save him
even with the Phoenix's power?
(I was still too late.)
(His soul)
(is probably already crossing
the River of Oblivion.)
(Once the dead
begin crossing the river,)
- (they can never come back to life.)
- River of Oblivion?
(River of Oblivion.)
(Ferrying Souls Across Oblivion.)
(Six steps to forget your past.)
(First step, forget fame and rank.)
(Second step, forget your knowledge.)
(Third step, forget
your closest friends.)
(Fourth step, forget your loved ones.)
(When you cross the River of Oblivion,)
(do not look back.)
♪I hate your back,
endless, blank, and never clear♪
♪Watching me weep, yet you stay silent♪
♪I hate how you cast me aside,
yet no room for a word♪
♪I hate my silence, my fading self,
and my lack of spite♪
♪Yet I still hope you'll save me♪
♪By the end,
I'm just your leftover compromise♪
♪All the excuses I made for you
are so absurd♪
♪My regret came too late,
I finally see your true face♪
♪My shattered promises struggle,
how can I let go♪
♪Stripped bare, tormented.
I flinch at every feeling♪
♪Forced to yield,
I flee before I fall apart♪
Mother.
Xi Yuan.
I can't forget either of you.
♪I hate how you cast me aside,
yet no room for a word♪
♪I hate my silence, my fading self,
and my lack of spite♪
♪Yet I still hope you'll save me♪
♪By the end,
I'm just your leftover compromise♪
♪All the excuses I made for you♪
Yunlie.
(Queen of Huyun Kingdom, Xing)
Mother.
Yunlie.
Mother, I've missed you so much.
Mother.
I've missed you so much.
Mother, I've missed you so much.
It's not safe to stay here.
Let's talk somewhere else.
Mother.
Come here.
Mother, I've missed you so much.
Good boy.
Come.
It's time for bed.
This is...
You were timid as a child
and never wanted to sleep alone.
Go to sleep.
Mother.
Ever since you died,
I've missed you so much.
My child.
All these years,
you've suffered so much.
Mother.
Since you haven't crossed
the River of Oblivion
and were able to wake me,
does that mean
we can go back together?
I've been a wandering spirit for years.
It was my obsession
that kept me lingering on until now.
Just now, I was only able
to bring you here with a secret art.
There's no chance I can return to life.
But Yunlie,
you can still go back.
Mother,
I'm taking you back with me.
My child,
we don't have much time.
I only have time
to tell you a few things.
Listen to me.
Your father
may have already fallen
to demonic corruption
and lost all sense of self and humanity.
♪A love letter, a passionate pursuit,
the envy of everyone♪
♪Bouquets and heartfelt confessions,
leaving me moved and fulfilled♪
♪No matter how long or hard our road,
I don't care♪
♪But you left me with this pain,
forever beyond redemption♪